[{
      "name": "Declaration and commenting",
      "id": "1001",
      "questions": [
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "How to declare a variable to hold an integer value?",
          "choices": [
            "var a;",
            "int a;",
            "a = 0",
            "num a;"
          ],
          "answer": "int a;"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "How to comment a single line?",
          "answer": "//"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "How to do a multi-line comment?",
          "choices": [
            "<!-- -->",
            "/* */",
            "#",
            "//"
          ],
          "answer": "/* */"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which is one of the way to declare a string constant?",
          "choices": [
            "char foo[] = \"foo\"",
            "String foo = \"foo\"",
            "chars foo = \"foo\"",
            "char foo=\"foo\""
          ],
          "answer": "char foo[] = \"foo\""
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "Name the data type to hold floating point(32-bit) numbers",
          "answer": "float"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "What is the qualifier used for representing only non-negative numbers?",
          "answer": "unsigned"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which storage class instructs the compiler to keep a local variable in existence during the life-time of the program instead of creating and destroying it each time it comes into and goes out of scope.",
          "choices": [
            "auto",
            "extern",
            "static",
            "register"
          ],
          "answer": "static"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which storage class is the default storage class for all local variables.",
          "choices": [
            "auto",
            "extern",
            "static",
            "register"
          ],
          "answer": "auto"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "___ allows you to combine data items of different kinds.",
          "choices": [
            "union",
            "struct",
            "enum",
            "typedef"
          ],
          "answer": "struct"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Operators",
      "id": "1002",
      "questions": [
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which is bitwise OR operator?",
          "choices": [
            "or",
            "xor",
            "|",
            "^"
          ],
          "answer": "|"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "___ is bitwise AND operator in C?",
          "answer": "&"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "___ is the bitwise operator used to get complement of a number in C?",
          "answer": "~"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which is conditional ternary operator?",
          "choices": [
            ">>",
            "?:",
            "<<",
            "??"
          ],
          "answer": "?:"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "Is there a way to increment and assign a value in a single statement?  If so, what is the operator?",
          "choices": [
            "No such operator",
            "+=",
            "=+",
            "&="
          ],
          "answer": "+="
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "How to multiply two numbers in C, say x, y are the numbers?",
          "choices": [
            "x . y",
            "x mul y",
            "x * y",
            "x ** y"
          ],
          "answer": "x * y"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Conditions and Loops",
      "id": "1003",
      "questions": [
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which is basic conditional branching statement in C?",
          "choices": [
            "check",
            "is",
            "if",
            "yes"
          ],
          "answer": "if"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "What is the syntax for FOR loop?",
          "choices": [
            "for ( variable initialization; condition; variable update )",
            "for ( condition; variable update ; exit status)",
            "for (condition 1; condition 2; condition 3)",
            "for ( variable increment ; variable decrement; condition )"
          ],
          "answer": "for ( variable initialization; condition; variable update )"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "Which looping makes sure loop is executed atleast once?",
          "choices": [
            "for",
            "while",
            "do..while",
            "None"
          ],
          "answer": "do..while"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "for (i = 0; i = 5; i++) { printf(\"%d\", i);} How many times will the statement inside the loop get executed?",
          "choices": [
            "5",
            "1",
            "6",
            "infinite"
          ],
          "answer": "infinite"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "What is the statement used to jump out of a loop",
          "answer": "break"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "What is the statement used to jump back to the beginning of the loop",
          "answer": "continue"
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "Say true or false.  default label in switch statement will be executed atleast once even if the condition in matches or not.",
          "answer": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "name": "Functions",
      "id": "1004",
      "questions": [
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "What is the return type of the function which does not return any value",
          "answer": "void"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "How to return two values from a function?",
          "choices": [
            "return a, b;",
            "return (a,b);",
            "return a:b;",
            "Not possible to return two values."
          ],
          "answer": "Not possible to return two values."
        },
        {
          "type": "blank",
          "question": "Say true or false.  Functions can return even a structure.",
          "answer": "true"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "What is the syntax for function declaration?",
          "choices": [
            "<return type> <function name>(<args>)",
            "<args> <function name>(<return type>)",
            "def <function name> (<args>)",
            "function <function name> (<args>, <return type>)"
          ],
          "answer": "<return type> <function name>(<args>)"
        },
        {
          "type": "choice",
          "question": "What is the signature of the function pointer which returns an int pointer and takes a char pointer as argument?",
          "choices": [
            "int (*fp)(char *)",
            "char * (*fp)(int *)",
            "int * (*fp)(char *)",
            "*fp (int *)(char *)"
          ],
          "answer": "int * (*fp)(char *)"
        }
      ]
    }]
